In this lesson, we will be exploring
本课将借助这个燃油效率数据集
bivariate visualizations through the use of this dataset on fuel efficiency.
来探索双变量可视化
The data consists of over 3900 sedans,
这里记录了 3900 辆轿车的数据
with manufacturing years from 2013 to 2018,
生产年份处于 2013 到 2018 年之间
and only considers conventional fuels.
只考虑常规燃料
Let's start by looking at the relationship between two quantitative variables,
我们先来研究两个数值变量之间的关系
the engine displacement in liters,
一个变量为发动机排量 单位为升
and the overall fuel mileage in miles per gallon.
另一个为燃油里程 单位为英里每加仑 (mpg)
Is a larger engine associated with a higher fuel efficiency or a lower one?
发动机排量越大 燃油效率是越高还是越低呢？
We can investigate this relationship using a scatter plot.
我们可以用散点图来研究这一关系
One way of creating a scatter plot is through Matplotlib's scatter function.
创建散点图的方法之一是使用 Matplotlib 的 scatter 函数
The arguments to this function are similar to what we've used before,
函数参数的设定和之前相似
but now we specify variables on both the X and Y axis.
但现在要同时指明 x 和 y 轴的变量
Set the data parameter to fuel_econ, X to
设参数 data 为 fuel_econ
dispel, and Y to comb,
设 x 为 displ 设 y 为 comb
for combined fuel efficiency.
即综合燃油效率 (combined fuel efficiency)
I'm also adding labels using X label,
我还要用函数 xlabel
and Y label to help keep track of the variables plotted on each axis.
和 ylabel 来创建标签 表明各轴上的变量分别是什么
The plot suggests a generally negative correlation
从图中可看出
between engine size and fuel efficiency.
发动机排量大小和燃油效率基本是负相关的
There's a large amount of variability for
但小排量的变化幅度
the smaller displacements compared to the larger ones.
要比大排量大
An alternative way of creating a scatter plot is through Seaborn's regplot function.
创建散点图还可以用 seaborn 的 regplot 函数
This function combines the creation of
该函数创建出来的散点图
a scatter plot with the fitting of a regression line to the data.
还带有数据的拟合回归线
To use it, just use the function sp.regplot instead of plt.scatter.
使用该函数时 我们只需将 plt.scatter 改为 sb.regplot 即可
Looking at the line, you can see how the cars with lower displacements,
观察这根回归线 不难发现小排量、高燃效的汽车
and higher efficiency, bring up the left side of the line.
拉高了线的左侧
You can turn off the regression line if you'd like,
你也可以取消回归线
by setting fit reg equals false.
只需将 fit_reg 设为 False 即可
You might have some questions about the data just looking at this plot.
观察这个散点图 你可能会产生一些疑问
The displacements are only listed to an accuracy of 0.1 liter.
图中排量只精确到 0.1 升
And since there's a lot of data to be plotted,
而要绘制的数据实在太多了
there might be a lot of overlapping points,
这就可能会有很多重叠的数据点
such that we don't really see the true relationship between variables and enough detail.
导致我们无法看出变量之间的真正关系 无法看清足够的细节
We'll get to techniques that addressed this concern in the upcoming videos
问题的解决办法请见下一个视频